How one man betrayed the security of a nation.
Breach is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Billy Ray.
Eric O'Neill, a low-level surveillance expert with the FBI, believes he is accomplishing his dream of becoming a full-fledged agent, with
his unexpected promotion and assignment to clerk for Robert Hanssen, a renowned senior agent with 25 years in the FBI.
However, he soon learns the reason for his promotion is to gain Hanssen's
trust and find proof that he is a traitor to the country.
Determined to draw the suspected double-agent out of deep cover,
O'Neill finds himself in a lethal game of spy vs.
spy, where nothing is as it seems.
Robert Hanssen, played by Chris Cooper.
Eric O'Neill, played by Ryan Phillippe.
Kate Burroughs, played by Laura Linney.
Juliana O'Neill, played by Caroline Dhavernas.
Rich Garces, played by Gary Cole.
Dean Plesac, played by Dennis Haysbert.
Breach is a 2007 American spy thriller film directed by Billy Ray, who
wrote the screenplay with Adam Mazer and William Rotko.
The film is based on the true story of Robert Hanssen, an FBI agent convicted of
spying for the Soviet Union and later Russia for more than two decades.
It stars Chris Cooper as Hanssen and Ryan Phillippe as Eric O'Neill, the
FBI investigator who helped bring about Hanssen's downfall.
The film received generally positive reviews and
grossed $41 million on a $23 million budget.
The film explores themes of undercover, spy, fbi, loyalty, suspicion.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.